(() => {
    let questions = [
        {
            questions: [
                {
                    question: "What was the religious make up of Ireland during the Tudor and Stuart period?",
                    correctAnswers: ["Almost completely Catholic"],
                    incorrectAnswers: ["Almost completely Protestant", "Almost equal numbers of Catholics and Protestants"]
                },
                {
                    question: "Like England and Scotland, Ireland had a major Protestant reformation during the Tudor and Stuart period. True or False?",
                    correctAnswers: ["False"],
                    incorrectAnswers: ["True"]
                },
                {
                    question: "Unlike England and Scotland, Ireland stayed an almost completely Catholic country during the Tudor and Stuart period. True or False?",
                    correctAnswers: ["True"],
                    incorrectAnswers: ["False"]
                },
            ]
        },
        {
            questions: [
                {
                    question: "Who extended English control outside the Pale and established English authority over the whole country?",
                    correctAnswers: ["Henry VII and Henry VIII"],
                    incorrectAnswers: [
                        "Elizabeth I and James I",
                        "Henry V and Henry VI",
                        "Edward I and Edward II",
                        "Richard II and Henry IV",
                        "Charles I and Charles II",
                        "James II and William III",
                        "Mary I and Elizabeth I"],
                    explanation: "This is what the book says, but may be a bit misleading. " +
                        "The Pale was extended during the reigns of Henry VII and Henry VIII, " +
                        "but it was not until the reign of James I that English authority was established over the whole country."
                },
                {
                    question: "What was the extent of English authority in Ireland after the actions of Henry VII and Henry VIII?",
                    correctAnswers: ["Over the whole country"],
                    incorrectAnswers: [
                        "Limited to the Pale",
                        "Only over Ulster",
                        "Only in Dublin and surrounding areas",
                        "Restricted to English settlements",
                        "Confined to the southern provinces",
                        "Limited to coastal regions"],
                    explanation: "This is what the book says, but may be a bit misleading. " +
                        "The Pale was extended during the reigns of Henry VII and Henry VIII, " +
                        "but it was not until the reign of James I that English authority was established over the whole country."
                },
            ]
        },
        {
            question: "Which English Monarch first took the title 'King of Ireland'?",
            correctAnswers: ["Henry VIII"],
            incorrectAnswers: ["Henry VII", "Elizabeth I", "James I", "Edward I", "Charles I", "William the Conqueror", "Richard III"]
        },
        {
            questions: [
                {
                    question: "During the time of Henry VIII, during the English control, what were local leaders in Ireland expected to follow?",
                    correctAnswers: ["The instructions of the Lord Lieutenants in Dublin"],
                    incorrectAnswers: [
                        "The rules of the Catholic Church",
                        "The guidance of the Scottish Parliament",
                        "The decrees of the King of France",
                        "The laws of the Spanish monarchy",
                        "The directions of the German emperor",
                        "The orders of the Pope in Rome"]
                },
                {
                    question:
                        "During the time of Henry VIII, during the English control, the local leaders in Ireland were expected to follow the instructions of the Lord Lieutenants." +
                        "Where were the Lord Lieutenants based?",
                    correctAnswers: ["Dublin"],
                    incorrectAnswers: ["London", "Edinburgh", "Belfast", "Cardiff", "Glasgow", "Manchester"]
                },
            ]
        },
        {
            question: "During the time of Henry VIII, during the English control, which legal system was introduced in Ireland?",
            correctAnswers: ["English laws"],
            incorrectAnswers: ["Scottish laws", "French laws", "Roman laws", "Spanish laws", "Irish traditional laws", "Dutch laws"]
        },
        {
            questions: [
                {
                    question: "During the reigns of Elizabeth I and James I, how did many people in Ireland respond to the rule by the Protestant government in England?",
                    correctAnswers: ["They opposed it"],
                    incorrectAnswers: [
                        "They supported it",
                        "They were indifferent to it",
                        "They were unaware of it",
                    ]
                },
                {
                    question: "What was the response of many people in Ireland to the rule by the Protestant government in England during the reigns of Elizabeth I and James I?",
                    correctAnswers: ["There were a number of rebellions"],
                    incorrectAnswers: [
                        "There was a peaceful integration",
                        "There was a large migration to England",
                        "There was a widespread acceptance of Protestantism",
                        "There was a declaration of independence"]
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            questions: [
                {
                    question: "Who did the English government encourage to settle in Ulster during the reign of Elizabeth I and James I?",
                    correctAnswers: ["Scottish and English Protestants"],
                    incorrectAnswers: [
                        "English and Irish Catholics",
                        "Scottish and Irish Protestants",
                        "Welsh and English Protestants",
                        "Scottish and Welsh Catholics",
                        "English and Welsh Catholics",
                        "Irish and Welsh Protestants"]
                },
                {
                    question: "Which part of Ireland did the Scottish and English Protestants settle in under the encouragement of the English government?",
                    correctAnswers: ["Ulster"],
                    incorrectAnswers: ["Leinster", "Munster", "Connacht", "Dublin", "Cork", "Belfast"]
                },
                {
                    question: "Where did many of the new settlers in Ulster come from during the plantations?",
                    correctAnswers: ["South-west Scotland"],
                    incorrectAnswers: ["North-east Scotland", "Wales", "Northern Ireland", "South-east England", "Midlands of England", "North-west England"]
                },
                {
                    question: "There were companies that were given land in Ulster during the plantations. Where were these companies based?",
                    correctAnswers: ["London"],
                    incorrectAnswers: ["Cardiff", "Dublin", "York", "Birmingham", "Norwich"]
                },
            ]
        },
        {
            question: "Whose land did the Scottish and English Protestants take over in Ulster?",
            correctAnswers: ["Catholic landholders"],
            incorrectAnswers: ["Protestant landholders", "Muslim landholders", "Jewish landholders", "Buddhist landholders", "Hindu landholders", "Sikh landholders"]
        },
        {
            question: "In what part of Ireland is Ulster?",
            correctAnswers: ["North"],
            incorrectAnswers: ["South", "East", "West", "Central"]
        },
        {
            questions: [
                {
                    question: "What were the English settlements in Ulster during the reigns of Elizabeth I and James I called?",
                    correctAnswers: ["Plantations"],
                    incorrectAnswers: ["Colonies", "Dominions", "Territories", "Provinces", "Estates", "Holdings"]
                },
                {
                    question: "In which Irish province were the plantations primarily established?",
                    correctAnswers: ["Ulster"],
                    incorrectAnswers: ["Leinster", "Munster", "Connacht", "Dublin", "Cork", "Limerick"]
                },
                {
                    question: "What did James I organise in several parts of Ireland, in addition to Ulster?",
                    correctAnswers: ["Plantations"],
                    incorrectAnswers: ["Military expeditions", "Trade agreements", "Religious reforms", "Educational institutions", "Cultural festivals", "Legal systems"]
                },
            ]
        },
        {
            question: "What was the outcome of the plantations and the English control established in Ireland during the reigns of Elizabeth I and James I?",
            correctAnswers: [
                "They had serious long term consequences for the history of England, Scotland, and Ireland."],
            incorrectAnswers: [
                "They led to immediate peace and prosperity in Ireland.",
                "They resulted in Ireland becoming independent.",
                "They caused no significant changes in England, Scotland, or Ireland.",
                "They were fully supported by all Irish people.",
                "They led to a significant decrease in English influence over Ireland."]
        },
    ];

    let category = {
        name: "Ireland",
        questions: questions,
        isUnvetted: true,
        group: "The Tudors and Stuarts"
    }
    quizDeck.categories.push(category);
})();
